<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Articles to be enquired of within the diocesse of Rochester in the first triennall visitation of the Right-Reverend Father in God, John, Lord Bishop of Rochester holden in the yeere of our Lord God 1638, in the fourteenth yeere of the reigne of Our Most Gratious Soveraigne Lord Charles, by the grace of God, King of Great Brttaine [sic], France and Ireland, defender of the faith, &amp;c.</title>
            <author>Church of England. Diocese of Rochester. Bishop (1637-1666 : Warner)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1638</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 32 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A00250</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 10321.5</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S869</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">22915401</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 22915401</idno>
            <idno type="VID">25876</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A00250)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 25876)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1777:15)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Articles to be enquired of within the diocesse of Rochester in the first triennall visitation of the Right-Reverend Father in God, John, Lord Bishop of Rochester holden in the yeere of our Lord God 1638, in the fourteenth yeere of the reigne of Our Most Gratious Soveraigne Lord Charles, by the grace of God, King of Great Brttaine [sic], France and Ireland, defender of the faith, &amp;c.</title>
                  <author>Church of England. Diocese of Rochester. Bishop (1637-1666 : Warner)</author>
                  <author>Warner, John, 1581-1666.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[15] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Richard Hodgkinsonne,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1638.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imperfect: pages cropped with some loss of print.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Magdalene College (University of Cambridge). Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Church of England --  Pastoral letters and charges.</term>
               <term>Visitations, Ecclesiastical --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Pip Willcox</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:25876:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:25876:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>ARTICLES TO BE Enquired of within the Dioceſſe of <hi>Rocheſter</hi> in the firſt Triennall Viſitation of the right-Reverend Father in GOD, <hi>John,</hi> Lord Biſhop of <hi>Rocheſter.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Holden in the yeere of our Lord God</hi> 1638. <hi>in the fourteenth yeere of the Reigne of our moſt gratious Soveraigne Lord</hi> CHARLES, <hi>by the Grace of</hi> GOD, <hi>King of Great</hi> Brttaine, France <hi>and</hi> Ireland, <hi>Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of the Faith, &amp;c.</hi> ⁂</p>
            <p>LONDON.</p>
            <p>Printed by <hi>Richard H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>dgeki<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </hi> 1638<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="oath">
            <pb facs="tcp:25876:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:25876:2"/>
            <head>The tenour of the Oath miniſtred to the Church-wardens and Sworn-men.</head>
            <p>YO<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g> ſhall ſweare, that all affection, favor, hatred hope of reward a<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>gaine, or feare of diſpleaſure, or malice, ſet aſide; you ſhall upon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> conſideration of the Articles given you in charge, preſent all and every ſi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> perſon, of, or within your Pariſh as hath committed any offence, or ma<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> any default mentioned in theſe, or any of theſe Articles, or any part branch of them, or which are vehemently ſuſpected, or otherwiſe defamed any ſuch offence, or fault; wherein you ſhall deale uprightly, and according truth; neither of malice preſenting any contrary to truth, nor of corrupt a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fection ſparing to preſent any, and ſo conceale the truth; having in this actio<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> God before your eyes, with an earneſt zeal to cheriſh virtue, and to ſuppreſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> vice: <hi>So helpe you GOD, and the Contents of this Booke.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="charge">
            <head>The charge of the Church-wardens and Sworn-men, ſet down for the better performance of their duties, and diſcharge of their Oathes.</head>
            <p>THey are ſtraightly charged to heare all theſe Articles read over to the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> and diligently to enquire thereof; and for that the time is ſo ſhort in th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Viſitation that they ſhall not be able to make a perfect anſwer unto them all: And that notwithſtanding there are many notorious faults preſently worthy of pre<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſentment and reformation, they are charged after their returne home, that, to<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>gether with their Miniſter, if he will joyn with them, they do read over all theſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Articles, deſtinctly and le<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rly, to the end they may conſider of every particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar Article or the offences in them contained, and of ſuch perſons in the pariſh as ſhall be noted to offend in any of them, and after that to aſſemble them<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſelves in ſome convenient time together and to make their Bill anſwering ever<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Article by it ſelfe; Which their Preſentment or Anſwer, they ſhall cauſe to delivered at the Regiſter his Office before the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> day of May next, or elſe for not delivering in thereof the Church-wardens and Sworn-m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> are admoniſhed to appeare that day at ten of the clock in the Conſiſtory at <hi>R<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cheſter,</hi> to alleage cauſe why they ſhould not be puniſhed for their negligence contempt therein.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="articles">
            <pb facs="tcp:25876:3"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:25876:3"/>
            <head>Articles to be enquired of within the Dioceſſe <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>Rocheſter,</hi> in the firſt Triennall-Viſitation of the right reuerend Father in God <hi>JOHN,</hi> Biſhop of <hi>Rocheſter,</hi> holden in the yeere of our Lord <hi>GOD 1638.</hi>
            </head>
            <div n="church" type="articles">
               <head>Articles concerning the Church.</head>
               <p>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hether have you in your pariſh-Churches and Chap<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> all things neceſſarie and requiſite for common-Pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap> and adminiſtration of the Sacraments, eſpecially <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> booke of common Prayer, with the new Kalender, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Homilies both firſt and ſecond Tome, a decent Sur<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap> a Table ſhewing what degrées of Conſanguinty and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>finity are forbiden in Marriage, ſet forth by authorit<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the yéere of our Lord God 1563. a faire paper book, wherein every Preac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> (which is a ſtranger and not Parſon, Vicar, or Curate, or ordinary preac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> there) ſhall write his name, the day he preacheth and by whoſe authority is Licenſed; the table of the ten Commandements; a convenient P<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap> well placed? A comely and decent Table, for the holy Communion, wi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> faire linnen cloath and ſome covering of Silke, or comely Carpet to lay<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> on the ſame; a faire and comely Communion-Cup of ſilver, and a cover of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ver for the ſame, which may ſerve alſo for the miniſtration of Communi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> bread; a comely pot to fetch Wine to ſerve the Lords Table, reſerved &amp; k<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> cleane to that uſe only, and a ſtrong Cheſt or Box for the almes of the po<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> with thrée locks and keyes to the ſame, and all other things neceſſary in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> to the premiſſes?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether are the afternoone Sermons in your ſeverall Pariſhes <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ned into Catechiſing by queſtion and anſwer; according to the forme <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſcribed in the booke of common Prayer; and whether doth every Lectu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> read divine Service according to the Liturgy printed by authority in Surplice and hood before the Lecture? and whether are his Majeſties <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſtructions in all things fully obſerved?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether any hath pulled down or uncovered your Church, Chan<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> or Chappell, or any part of them, or hath pulled down the Bels? whethe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> your Church or Chappell and the Chancell, well and ſufficiently repaire<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> whether doth your Parſon, Vicar, or Curate of your Parſonage or Vicar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> in your pariſh, kéep the Parſonage or Vicarage-houſe (with all other the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>es
<pb facs="tcp:25876:4"/>
thereunto apperteining) in good and ſufficient reparations? And whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> is your Church-yard well fenced and cleanly kept, without any la<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſtall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ther annoyances?</p>
               <p>Whether your Fonts or Baptiſteries be removed from the place where <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> were wont to ſtand? or whether any Parſons (leaving the uſe of them) Chriſten in Baſons, or other veſſels, or have taken down the old uſuall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>at, heretofore uſed in your pariſh? and whether you have decent Fonts <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> coverings for them?</p>
               <p>Whether is therin your pariſh a ſufficient Regiſter book of parchment Chriſtnings Mariages and Burials, provided at the charge of the pariſh? <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ther are all the names of thoſe that have béen either Chriſtened, Maried, Buried ſince the begining of her late Majeſties reigne, newly written into ſaid parchment booke? whether doth the Miniſter every Sunday read the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>nes publiquely, of thoſe that were either Chriſtened, Married or Buries wéek before? whether have you a publique Cheſt with thrée locks, for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>niſter and the two Church-wardens to kéep the ſaid book in, and whether <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>e you brought a Tranſcript of all the names of ſuch as have béen Chriſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>, Married, and Buried this laſt yéere, into the Regiſters office, as you are <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>nd to do every yéere hereafter (within a moneth after the feaſt of Eaſter) <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>he Conſtitutions?</p>
               <p n="6">6 Is your Church or Chappell decently paved and is your Church-yard <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ll and orderly kept without abuſe? are the bones of the dead decently in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>red, or layd up in ſome place fit, as beſéemeth Chriſtians; and is the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ole conſecrated ground kept frée from Swine and all other naſtines as be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>nes the place ſo dedicated.</p>
               <p n="7">7 Whether your Communion Table be decently rayled in whereby the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>mmunicant and may receive the holy Sacrament knéeling in an humble man<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> have you a carpet of ſilke or ſome other decent ſtuffe and a faire linnen <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>th to lay thereon at the Communion time, and is the ſame table ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>r out of the time of divine Service, or in it abuſed by ſitting, writing, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>wing Hatts on it; or any other wayes prophaned.</p>
               <p>Whether have any Monuments or Glaſſe windowes béen defaced or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>ſe inſcriptions, lead, ſtones or any thing elſe belonging to your Church, Chapell béene at any time purloyned and by whom?</p>
               <p>Whether have you the Terrier of all the Gleab-lands, meadowes, gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>s, orchards, houſes, ſtocke, implements, tenements and portions of tithes <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ther within your Pariſh or without, belonging to your Parſonage or Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>g taken by the view of honeſt men in your ſaid pariſh? &amp; whether the ſame <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>rrier be laid up in the Regiſtry of the Biſhop and in whoſe hands any of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>n now are? and if you have already no Terrier made in Parchment the Church-wardens and Side-men together with the Parſon or Vicar
<pb facs="tcp:25876:4"/>
or in his abſence with your Miniſter are to make deligent inquire, and ſentment of the premiſes, and make, ſubſcribe, and ſigne the ſaid Terrie aforeſaid?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="clergy" type="articles">
               <head>Concerning the Clergy.</head>
               <p>Whether is the whole Service or Common-prayer read in your Chu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> or Chappell, diſtinctly and reverently, upon all Sundayes and H<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dayes in ſuch order as is ſet down in the booke of common Prayer, with<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> any kinde of alteration or omiſſion, and at due and convenient houres?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether have you any Lecturer in your pariſh who will not prof<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> his willingnes to take upon him a Living or Benefice with Cure of ſo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> or who hath refuſed a Benefice when it hath béene offered unto him.</p>
               <p n="3">3 Hath your Miniſter or any other Preacher baptized children churc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> any woman, or miniſtred the holy Communion in any privat houſe otherw<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> then by Law is alowed?</p>
               <p n="4">4 Doth your Miniſter endeavour and labour diligently to reclaime <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> popiſh Recuſants in his Pariſh from their errours if there be any ſuch a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ding in your pariſh? or whether is your Parſon, Vicar or Curate over-c<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>verſant with, or a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>vourer of Recuſants whereby he is ſuſpected not to ſincere in Religion.</p>
               <p n="5">5 Hath your Miniſter taken upon him to appoint any publike or priv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> faſts prophecies or exerciſes not approved by Law or publike authority or ha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> uſed to méet in any privat houſe or place with any perſon or perſons, the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> to conſult how to impeach or deprave the booke of common Prayer, or the d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ctrine, or diſcipline of the Church of <hi>England.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="6">6 Whether doth your Miniſter upon Wedneſdaies and Fridaies (not b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing holy dayes) read in your Church or Chappell the Letany and other Pra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ers appointed in the ſaid booke for thoſe dayes? And whether doth he ſom<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>time reade the Commination againſt Sinners, in ſuch order and forme <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> is there preſcribed</p>
               <p n="7">7 Whether doth your Parſon, Vicar or Curat, in the adminiſtration the Lords Supper, of Baptiſme, in the ſolemnization of Marriage Buriall the dead, churching of Women, &amp;c. uſe the formes prayers and ceremoni<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> preſcribed in the Communion book; as namely, whether doth he adminiſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> the Communinon to none but ſuch as do knéele at the receiving thereof; ma<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> the ſigne of the Croſſe upon the Childes fore-head, in the adminiſtration <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Baptiſme; baptize any without Godfathers and Godmothers; uſe the Ri<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> in Mariage; and generally, whether doth he in the diſchargeing of all the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> duties (and when he readeth common-Prayer upon Sundayes &amp; Holy-daie<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> weare a Surplice?</p>
               <p n="8">
                  <pb facs="tcp:25876:5"/>8 Whether doth your Miniſter or Curate refuſe to baptize Children pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ly that are in danger of death, if they be thereunto required; and have any <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ldren died without Baptiſme by their default, or do they refuſe to ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>niſter the holy Communion to thoſe that lie on their death-beds and deſire <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſame?</p>
               <p n="9">9 Whether doth your Miniſter or Curat, in their Sermons or otherwiſe <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ny other, ſpeake againſt the neceſſitie or benefit of the Sacraments, If <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>y may conveniently be had?</p>
               <p n="10">10 Whether doth your Miniſter upon Sundayes at Morning prayer; de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>re unto the Pariſhioners what Holy-dayes &amp; Faſting-dayes are appointed <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e kept the wéek following, according to the Lawes of this Realme?</p>
               <p n="11">11 Whether doth your Miniſter in the Rogation wéek uſe the perambula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>n of the circuit of your Pariſh, appointed by the Law?</p>
               <p n="12">12. Whether doth any man, being neither Miniſter nor Deacon, reade <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>mmon-Prayer openly in your Church or Chappell, or adminiſter the Sacra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>nts or ſolemnize Matrimonie, or take upon him to practiſe any other mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>riall duty in the Church, which is preſcribed to be executed particularly by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>h as are either Miniſters or Deacons, and what is his name that ſo doth?</p>
               <p n="13">13 Whether is your Parſon Vicar or Curat a Preacher, licenſed to preach <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> lawfull authority? if he be, how many Sermons doth he preach yéerly? if <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> be not, how many doth he procure to be preached by others? who hath <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ached them? and whether were they Preachers licenſed, as is before e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>ſſed?</p>
               <p n="14">14 Whether doth your Parſon Vicar or Curat, every Sunday and Holy-<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>y (when there is no Sermon) reade, diſtinctly and plainly, ſome part of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>omilies preſcribed and ſet forth by authority?</p>
               <p n="15">15 Whether doth the Parſon or Vicar or your Pariſh, cauſe or ſuffer any <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>rat or miniſter, either to read Service, &amp;c. or to preach, before he the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Curate, be examined and admitted by the Ordinary in writing, and before <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the ſaid Curate be thereunto admitted according to law?</p>
               <p n="16">16 Whether doth your Preacher in his prayer which he maketh at his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>rmon, uſe to pray for his Maieſty, with his whol Title, for our gracious <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>éene, the Prince, and whether doth he in like manner, then pray for the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>h-Biſhops and Biſhops, as by Law is alſo appointed?</p>
               <p n="17">17 Whether doth your Miniſter ſerve two Cures in one day?</p>
               <p n="18">18 Whether your Miniſter or any other having taking holy orders, hold <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> conventicles or doth preach in any place, or doth uſe any other forme of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>ne Service then is appointed in the booke of common Prayer?</p>
               <p n="19">19 Doth your Miniſter Curat or Lecturer in his or their Sermons de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>r ſuch Doctrine as may tend to obedience and edifying their audito<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> faith and religion without intermedling with matters of ſtate not fit
<pb facs="tcp:25876:5"/>
to be handled in the Pulpit but to be diſcuſſed by the wiſdome of his Mo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> and his Councell, and if you finde any herein faulty yée ſhall preſent th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </p>
               <p n="20">20 Whether doth your Parſon Vicar or Curat, every Sunday and l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> day, openly in the Church earneſtly call for, heare and inſtruct all the chil<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> apprentices and ſervant, of both ſeres, that be of convenient age within <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> pariſh, or at the leaſt ſo many of them by courſe as the time will ſerve, a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> be may well heare and inſtruct before Evening Prayer, in the ten Com<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dements, the Articles of the Beliefe, and the Lord Prayer, &amp; diligently <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> mine, and teach them the Catechiſme, as if is now alowed and ſet forth, i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> book of common Prayer?</p>
               <p n="21">21 Whether is ther any man in your Pariſh, being neither your Pa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Vicar, nor Curat, that taketh upon him to Preach or reade Lectures, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> is not licenſed thereunto, or who doth not once a yéere (at the leaſt) reade<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> whole Service as it is preſcribed in the book of common-Prayer, and ad<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>niſter both the Sacraments in your ſaid Church or Chappell where h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> preacheth or readeth, according to the booke of common-Prayer?</p>
               <p n="22">22 Whether your Miniſter hath or doth receive to the holy-Commun<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> any perſons that be not of his own pariſh, and whether they be Sectuarie<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> otherwiſe infamous, or ſtained in Religion?</p>
               <p n="23">23 Whether doth your Parſon, Vicar or Curate, reject any from the h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Communion, and for what cauſes?</p>
               <p n="24">24 Whether hath your Parſon, Vicar or Curat, or any other Miniſter<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> party whatſoever, publiquely or privatly preached, or ſpoken any thing in<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rogation of the booke of common-Prayer, by diſprayſing or depraving <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſame, or any thing therein conteined, or againſt the preſent eſtate of the Ec<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſiaſticall government eſtabliſhed by authority, or againſt any office, funct<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> or part thereof, affirming the ſame to be unlawfull, popiſh, or antichriſtian <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </p>
               <p n="25">25 Whether hath your Parſon or Vicar more benefices then one? I<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> hath not, whether is he reſident upon that one? If he be not reſident, wh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> doth he remaine? And whether doth he leave a ſufficient Miniſter and Pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cher to ſupply his abbſence, allowing ſomething yéerly towards the relief the poore? And what doth he ſo allow,</p>
               <p n="26">26 Whether is your Parſon or Vicar, who hath two benefices within <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Dioces, or one Benefice in this Dioces, and another forth of the ſame, reſid<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> one halfe of the yéere on one of them, and the other halfe yéere, or the grea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> part thereof upon his other Benefice? And whether doth he leave the Be<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fice in your pariſh provided of a ſufficient Preacher to ſerve it, and hath a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſpeciall care of ſome convenient hoſpitaility to be kept in his abſence, ac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ding to his ability and the proportion of his living?</p>
               <p n="27">27 Whether doth your Parſon Vicar or Curat, uſe ſuch decent and co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <pb facs="tcp:25876:6" rendition="simple:additions"/>Whether doth your Parſon Vicar or Curat, kéepe any man or woman <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>eir houſes, who are ſuſpected to be, either of evill Religion, or of bad <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> whether be they or any of them negligent perſons themſelves, or given <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ankenneſſe, or to be hunters of Taverns, Ale-houſes, or ſuſpected places <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>mon Dicers Swearers, or other wiſe ſuſpected perſons of any notorious <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>e, or light and unſéemly behaviour, or give evill example of life?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="ecclesiastical officers" type="articles">
               <head>Eccleſiaſticall Magiſtrates and Officers</head>
               <p>WHether hath any perſon within your Pariſh, promiſed or paid any ſumme of money or other reward, directly or indirectly by him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe or any other, to any Iudge or Officer of the Eccleſiaſticall Court, for avoyding puniſhment for any Inceſt, Adultry, Forni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n, or any other Eccleſiaſticall Crime; if ſo, then with whom, when or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hat ſumme?</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Item,</hi> hath any Chancellor, Arch-Deacon, Officiall or any other exerci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> Eccleſiaſticall Iuriſdiction within the Dioces; or any Regiſter Appari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>or Miniſter belonging to the ſame Eccleſiaſticall Court, exacted extraor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>rily, or taken greater Fées then heretofore of late hath béen accuſtomed? <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> whether is there a Table of the Rates of al the Fées ſet up in their ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap> Courts or Offices; And whether they or any of them, have taken upon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the Office of Informers or Promoters to the Courts, or any other way <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ed themſelves in their Office, contrary unto the Law and Canons in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> caſe provided?</p>
               <p>Hath any perſon within your Pariſh paied or promiſed any ſumme of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>ey or other reward for commutation of penance for any crime of Eccle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="6 letters">
                     <desc>••••••</desc>
                  </gap>call cogniſance? if ſo then by whom, when and for what and how hath <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ame béene imployed?</p>
               <p>Have any Eccleſiaſticall Iudges, or their ſubſtitutes heard any matters <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ffice or correction privatly in their Chambers without their ſworne Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>rs or their deputies preſence?</p>
               <p>Have theſe other Recuſants or any belonging to the Eccleſiaſticall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>rt exacted extraordinary or greater fées then heretofore hath béen accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ed, in what manner; whether is a table of the rate of fées ſet up in their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>rall Courts and Offices, or whether they or any of them have any way <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>d themſelves in their Offices contrary to the Law and Canons in that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> provided? whether have they threatned any to preſent them in the ſaid <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>rt if they would not give them ſome rewards: and what in thiz or the like <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap>e have they taken?</p>
               <p>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 line">
                     <desc>〈1 line〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb facs="tcp:25876:6"/>
and in what manner is the country overburdened and grieved by the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Apparitors?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="physicians, surgeons and midwives" type="articles">
               <head>Phyſitions and Chyrurgions and Mid-wives</head>
               <p>HOw many Phyſitians, Chirurgions and Mid-wives have you in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Pariſh? how long have they uſed their ſeverall Sciences or Off<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and by what authority? and how have they demeaned themſelves; the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> and of what ſkill are they accounted to be in their profeſſions?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="schoolmasters" type="articles">
               <head>Articles concerning Schoolemaſters.</head>
               <p>WHether every Schoolemaſter within your pariſh in any Nobl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Gentlemans houſe, or in any other place, be of good and ſin<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> Religion, Life and Converſation, and be diligent in teaching <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> bringing up of youth; and whether they have béene examin<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> allowed and licenſed <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Schoolemaſtrs, by the Ordinary in that behalf?</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether your Schoolemaſter or Schoolmaſters, do themſelves rece<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> the holy Communion as often as they ought to do, and whether do all th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Schollers which be of age ſufficient, and of capacity, by inſtructions com<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> the Communion, either in your own Church, or elſe where their Pare<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> dwell, once every yéere, and be diligent to heare common Prayer?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether the Schoolemaſter or Schoolemaſters, either privat or publi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> do teach their Schollers the Catechiſme authorized by publique Authority <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> the leaſt once every wéeke, and do inſtruct and examine them in the ſame <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> do teach any other Catechiſme? &amp; what Catechiſme is that they ſo do teach<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether your Schoolemaſter or Schoolemaſters, or any of them <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> known or ſuſpected to read unto their Schollers privatly, any unlawfull bo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> or privatly to inſtruct them in their yong yéeres, either in popery, ſuperſtio<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> or diſobedience, or contempt to his Majeſty and his Lawes Eccleſiaſticall<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> publique authority allowed?</p>
               <p n="5">5 Doth any teach or kéepe Schoole in the Chancell or Church by w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> meanes that holy place or the Communion Table may be prophaned, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> windowes broken?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="parishioners" type="articles">
               <head>Articles concerning the Pariſhioners, and others of the Laitie.</head>
               <p>WHether all houſholders in your pariſh, cauſe their Children, Serv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and Apprentices, both mankinde and womankinde, being abo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> yéeres of age, and under 21 which have not ſo learned the Cachiſme, to e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb facs="tcp:25876:7"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he Church on Sundayes and Holy-dayes at the time appointed for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>techiſing, and there diligently and obediently to heare? and what be the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nes of thoſe that do not cauſe their children, ſervants and apprentices <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> come to the Church to be examined?</p>
               <p>Whether there be any in your pariſh, who will come to heare the Sermon <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> will not come to publicke to prayers appointed by the booke of common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>yer making a Schiſme or diviſion (as it were) betwéene the uſe of pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Prayer and Preaching?</p>
               <p n="3">3 Whether any not being in holy Orders do execute any prieſtly or mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>iall office in your Church Chappell, or Church-yard and what be their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>es</p>
               <p n="4">4 Have any libelled or ſpoken ſlanderous words againſt your miniſter to <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſcandall of his vocation?</p>
               <p n="5">5 Whether the fift day of November be kept holy and thankſgiving m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>e <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> God for his Majeſties and this States happy deliverance according to the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>dinance in that behalfe?</p>
               <p n="6">6 Whether any in your pariſh have Married within the degrées by Law pro<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ited, and where and by whom? and whether any couple in you<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Pariſh he<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> lawfully married, live apart one from the other without due ſeparation the Law or any that have béene divorced which kéep company with any <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>er at bed or at boord?</p>
               <p n="7">7 Whether any withhold the ſtock of the Church or any goods or any other <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ngs given to good and charitable uſes.</p>
               <p n="8">8 Whether there be any perſon or perſons Eccleſiaſticall or Temporall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>thin your pariſh, or elſewhere within this Dioceſſe, that have reteined and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>t in their cuſtody, or that read, ſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>l, utter, diſpearce, earry or diliver to o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>rs, any Engliſh books or Libels ſet forth either on this ſide, or beyond the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>as, by Papiſts or Sectaries againſt the Kings Supremacy, in cauſes Ec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ſiaſticall, or againſt true Religion and Catholique Doctrine now publique<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> profeſſed in this Church, or the government or diſcipline of the Church of <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>gland,</hi> now within this Realme received and eſtabliſhed by common autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>, and what their names and ſirnames are?</p>
               <p n="9">9 Whether there be in your pariſh any popiſh or ſectary Recuſant or Re<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ants, which for any cauſe whatſoever, forbeare to come to Church or com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n Prayer, and what their ſeverall name or names are, and how long they <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e béen Recuſants?</p>
               <p n="10">10 Whether doth any refuſe to receive the holy Communion at their own <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>niſters hands, either becauſe he is not a Preacher, or becauſe he duely ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>eth the order of adminiſtration appointed by the book of common Prayer, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> who they be that do go from their own Pariſh, to receive at any other Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> Pariſh upon the day which the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb facs="tcp:25876:7" rendition="simple:additions"/>
have received the bleſſed Sacrament, uſe or reſort to Ale-houſes, or o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="4 letters">
                     <desc>••••</desc>
                  </gap> places or actions unfit?</p>
               <p n="11">11 Whether any of your pariſhioners do abſent themſelves from their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Church, and reſort to any other place to heare other Preachers, and for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> cauſe?</p>
               <p n="12">12 Whether all the people of your pariſh above 16 yéeres of age, and e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cially houſhoulders, having no lawfull excuſe to be abſent, do reſort with <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſervants and children to their pariſh Church or Chappell on the Sundaies <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Holydaies to Morning and Evening-Prayer, &amp; who they be, that either <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ligently or wilfully abſent themſelves, or do unreverently behave themſel<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> in the Church as men at the time of Prayers, Sermon, and adminiſtra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> of the Sacraments to ſit bare?</p>
               <p n="13">13 Whether there de any In-kéepers, Ale-wives, Victuallers, or Tipl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> that ſuffer or do admit any perſon or perſons in their houſes, to eate dr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> or play at Dice, Cards, Tables, Bowles or ſuch like games, in the tim<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> common-Prayer or Sermon, on the Sundaies and Holy-dayes; or any <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>chers or other that commonly uſe to ſell meate or other things in the time <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> common-Prayer, Preaching, or reading of Homilies: and whether in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Faires or common Markets, falling upon the Sundayes, there be ſhew<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> of any wares: and whether any Markets and ſelling of wares be uſed or ſu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>red in any Church-yeard on the Sunday?</p>
               <p n="14">14 Whether the Churchwardens and Sworn-men have concealed <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> crime or other diſorder in their time done in your pariſh, and have not <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſented the ſame to the Biſhops, Chancellor, Arch-Deacon, Commiſſary, or ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> others that had authority to reforme the ſame; and whether they or any <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> them, at any ſuch time as they ſhould have béene at divine Service on S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>dayes and Holydaies, and ſhould there have obſerved others that were ſent, have béen a way themſelves?</p>
               <p n="15">15 Whether there be any in your Pariſh, that have not fulfilled th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> Teſtators laſt Will, in paying of Legacies given to the Church, or to of<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> good and godly uſes; as to the reliefe of poverty or Orphants, poore Schol<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> poore maidens marriages, high wayes and ſuch like, and by whom they a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> denyed?</p>
               <p n="16">16 Whether there be among you any Blaſphemers of the name of G<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> great or often Swearers, Adulterers, Fornicators, Harlots or Whormaſt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:punc">▪</g>  Inceſtuous perſons, Bawdes, or receivers of naughty and incontinent ſons or harborers of women with childe which be unmarried, conveyin<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſuffering them to go away before they do any penance; or any that are vi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>montly ſuſpected of any ſuch fault?</p>
               <p n="17">17 Whether the Miniſter and Churchwardens have ſuffered any Fe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 line">
                     <desc>〈1 line〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb facs="tcp:25876:8"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>mmer Lord or Ladie or any diſguiſed perſons, &amp; players of May-games <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ay Morriſdancers, at any time to come irreverently into the Church or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>rch-yeard, and there to dance or play, or ſhew themſelves diſguiſed, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>t they be that commit ſuch diſorder, or that accompanied or maintained <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n, or any Playes diſorders or prophanations to be commited in the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>rch?</p>
               <p n="18">18 Whether therebe any married women, or others within your pariſh <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>th after child-birth refuſe, to come to the Church in decent ſort to give God <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ks for their delivery, and to heare the Prayers publikely appointed in <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> behalfe by the book of common-Prayer?</p>
               <p n="19">19 Whether any within your pariſh do reſort unto Barns, Fields, Woods, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>at houſes or any other place, for expoſition of Scriptures or conferences <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ether, or that be drawers or perſwaders of others to any ſuch ſchiſmaticall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>venticles?</p>
               <p n="20">20 Whether any do kéepe their childeren unbaptized longer then is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ient, and whether any do carry their children from the Pariſh they are <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ne in, to other pariſhes to be baptized, and to refuſe their own pariſh, or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ring ſtrange Miniſters into their own houſes to baptize their children <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>atly acording to their own fantaſies?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="churchwardens" type="articles">
               <head>Concerning Church-wardens and Sidemen.</head>
               <p>WHether the Church-wardens and Sidemen do, &amp; have done their beſt endevors to reſtrein idle perſons from wandring, playing, or tipling the time of divine Service or Sermon, and whether they cauſe the inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ants and other in the pariſh as much as in them is to reſort to divine Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e and Sermon.</p>
               <p n="2">2 Whether the Church-wardens do preſent all thoſe who do not ſend <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ir Children and Servants to be Catechiſed.</p>
               <p n="3">3 What unmarried woman being gotten with child is gone out of your <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>iſh before they might be preſented to the Ordinarie or might have done <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ir penance and out of whoſe houſes have they ſo departed.</p>
               <p n="4">4 Whether and how often have yée ſuffered any to Preach within your <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>urch or Chappell who was not ſufficiently licenced thereunto<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> you take not the beſt care that every pariſhioner having paſſed the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ces of age receive the holy Communion thrice every yeere and that no <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nger uſually come to your Church from their own Pariſh.</p>
               <p n="5">5 Have you at every Communion in your Church or Chappell good pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>on of Bread and Wine, and thoſe decently brought preſerved and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ed.</p>
               <p n="6">
                  <pb facs="tcp:25876:8"/>6 Are there any Legacies with-holden which were given to the Ch<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> in whoſe hands are theſe by whom, were they given, and by whom are <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> with-held? and are the Almes of the Church faithfully diſtributed to the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>of the poore.</p>
               <p n="7">7 Doe yée know of any thing complained of that hath not béene redreſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="parish clerk and sexton" type="articles">
               <head>Pariſh Clark and Sexton.</head>
               <p>HAve you a fit Pariſh Clark of honeſt converſation able to read ſing <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> write? are his and the Sextons wages duly payed unto them accord to the antient cuſtome of the Pariſh; by whom are they choſen: and be t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> approved of by the Ordinary, be they diligent in their Office and Serv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>able to the Miniſter and do either of them take upon them to medle with <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> thing above his Office as churching women buring the dead or the like?</p>
               <p>Doth your Clark or Sexton kéep the Church cleane and the dores lock at fit times? is any thing loſt or ſpoiled in the Church through his defar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> are the Communion Table, Font, Books, and other Ornaments of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> Church kept faire and cleane?</p>
            </div>
            <div n="Bill of Presentment" type="proforma">
               <p>AT the delivery of your Bill of Preſentment, you are likewiſe to ſet down,
<table>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Recuſants, Men</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Recuſants, Women</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Non-Communicants of both ſexes</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Communicants of both ſexes in the whole Pariſh</cell>
                        <cell> </cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
To which the Miniſter, Churchwardens, and Side-men, muſt put their han<gap reason="illegible" resp="#PDCC" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </p>
            </div>
            <trailer>FINIS</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
